卡多语
没事的 孩子…
我知道你希望这一切终结
我就在这儿
我会在这儿…
但是 你不能放弃
听到没有
只要你仍存一丝呼吸 就别放弃
你要呼吸着… 一直呼吸着
霍克
Hawk.
别动
靠
Oh shit!
狗娘养的
God damn sons of bitches.
真他妈的
God shit me more.
- 你看寇特了吗？- 没
- Hey you seen Coulter? - No.
听好了 皮子处理干净之后
Listen up! When them pelts is clean...
你们要把皮子包得紧紧的
I want you to wrap them up real tight.
记住了 我们不是15张一捆
Remember, We're not doing no 15 pelt bales...
- 我们是30张一捆 - 菲兹杰拉德
- We're doing 30 pelt bales. - Fitzgerald.
- 队长 - 我们的货这才运到哪儿
- Captain. - Where are we with the haul?
你想什么呢
What are you thinking?
这个…
Well...
我在想 无论他们在那儿打什么
I'm thinking whatever it is that they're hunting out there...
希望他们不用再补一枪了
I'm hoping they don't need another shot.
咱们要确保黄昏前上路
Let's make sure we're at ahead by dawn.
我们今早就已经完事儿了
We've been done by this morning.
我自己也不喜欢呆这儿 但你知道我们也没辙
I don't like to be not here myself by now, but you know we're not.
我们的人都太累了
We men are too tired.
我觉得我们才出了堡子几天 就困在这里
I figure we're only few days out from the Fort, we're trapped out.
我们现在只担心
All we have to worry about...
- 怎么给小伙子们弄到新鲜的肉 - 是啊
- is getting some fresh meat for the boys. - Yeah.
是啊 你看寇特了吗
Yeah, you seen Coulter?
嘿 我们放倒一只麋鹿
Hey, we took down an elk.
挺肥实
A big one.
我们需要人帮忙把肉拉回去
We're gonna need some help to haul the meat back.
你真是哪壶不开提哪壶
You let me know when it's on the spit.
我回头会帮你的
I'll help with it then.
嘿 别介 得了哥们儿… 我需要你搭把手
Hey no, come on fellas... I need your help.
我们忙着给皮子打捆 也需要搭把手来着
We needed help when we were busting are asses loading them bales.
我在这儿吃了好久河狸肉了
I've been out here so long eating this damn beaver meat...
竟然开始怀念我老婆做的菜了
I'm actually starting to miss my wife's cooking.
靠 我竟然开始怀念你老婆了
Shit, I'm actually starting to miss your wife.
为什么不闭上你的狗嘴
Why don't you shut the hell?...
救命
Help.
那是不是寇特？
Is that Coulter?
- 都聚在一起 - 吉姆 你去找队长
- Stay together. - Jim, you go get the Captain.
天啊
Jesus Christ!
- 别说了 - 帮帮他
- Shut up! - Help him!
- 有人看清楚了吗？- 都他妈安静
- Anybody seeing them? - Stay quiet damm it...
我操
God damn.
怎么了
爸
快走
托马斯也死了
They got Thomas.
我看不着他们
I can't see them.
- 卧倒 - 我靠
- Get down. - Oh shit.
他们到处都是
They are everywhere.
我们被包围了
We are surrounded.
- 他们到处都是 - 索赫…
- They're everywhere. - Soho...
待在这里别动
Stay here.
不 不 哦不
No, no. Oh no!
- 别起来 - 救命
- Stay down. - Help me!
他们想引诱我们暴露
They want us out in the open...
来个人到坡上去
Someone get up the hill!
谁也别动 待在原地
Nobody move, just stay where you are.
看来他们想要皮子
Well they want the pelts.
我们要么现在冲上去拼了
We go and get on them about right now...
要么失去一切
or we gonna lose it all.
到船那儿去 去船那儿 孩子
Get to the boat. To the boat, son.
走 走 走
Move, move, move.
离开树林 离开树林
Leave the forest, leave the forest...
去船那儿
To the boat.
霍克
Hawk!
霍克 霍克
Hawk, Hawk!
抄上点皮子
Grab some pelts!
来 抄上皮子
Come on, grab the pelt!
抄上皮子
Grab the pelt.
来
Come on.
把这个给我女儿
Get this to my little girl.
我们不会抛弃你 我会找人帮忙…
You're coming with us I'm getting help...
扶着我 把…
Lean on me, just get...
格拉斯
Glass!
去船那儿
Get to the boat!
你他妈个狗娘…
You fucking son of a...
快他妈上船
Get on the fucking boat.
救命
Help.
走 上啊
Move, come on.
来
Come on.
切断绳子
Cut the rope.
- 切断绳子 - 等等阿莫斯 等等阿莫…
- Cut the rope. - Wait for Amos, wait for Amos...
我们现在就得走
We go now.
去大炮那儿
Go to the cannon.
别走 求你们
Don't leave, please.
我的女儿波瓦卡不在这儿
能拿走的皮子都带上
我们要拿皮子和法国人换马 然后不停的寻找她
尘土会化为鲜花…
And the dust becomes flower...
阿门
Amen.
当早晨那样清净…
When the morning was clear...
阿门
Amen.
准备
Ready?
别动
Hold still.
你从哪儿学的这手？
Where did you learn that?
我父亲曾是医生
My father was a doctor.
- 布里杰 - 队长 我们这儿有个土著
- Bridger. - Captain we got a small tree niggers out here...
正等着干活呢
Waiting to finish the job.
- 把住了 - 好
- Hold there. - Yes.
告诉我你有些个计划了
Tell me you got some kind of plan.
格拉斯
Glass.
不能走密苏里河
Missouri is no good.
里族还盯着我们就走不了
Not while the Rees running it.
我们得下船
We got to get off this boat...
哦 你想下船
Oh you want to get off the boat?
那我们怎么办 哈
Then what we're gonna do, hah?
我们就拿着皮子
We're gonna take our furs...
坐在里族地盘里 像一群肥鸭一样
And sit out there amongst the Ree, like a bunch of god damn ducks.
唯一安全的方法是开辟一条新路
Only safe thing to do is track a new course...
回到陆地上
back upon land.
我们的行程会拖慢几个星期
We'll add weeks to the trip.
那也好过这就么漂到他们眼皮子底下
Better than floating back down there where they can get their eyes on us.
你现在就在人眼皮底下 孩子
They got eyes on you right now, son.
要我说 咱们就待在船上
What I'm saying is we stay on the boat.
试试到堡子的水路
Try the course toward the Fort...
咱们在河上碰碰运气
We take the chances on the water.
格拉斯比我们加起来还要熟悉这一片儿
Glass knows this territory better than the rest of us put together.
他的职责就是带我们安全回家
It's his job to get us home safe.
- 带我们安全回家 - 是啊
- Get us home safe? - Yeah.
需要我提醒你咱们已经失去了32个人了吗
Need I remind you we already lost 32 men?
现在33个了
33 now.
他们是我的人 菲兹杰拉德 我知道我失去了多少
They were my men, Fitzgerald, I know how many I lost.
我们就按格拉斯说的做 就这么定了
We do like Glass says, that's the end of it.
我们得把船系松一点
We have to set the boat loose.
如果里族还在跟踪我们 他们会在下游找到船
If Ree are tracking us, they will find it down the river.
最佳路线是深入陆地 沿地势向下走
The best course is hike in on the ground and follow it down...
直至卡河瓦堡
to Fort Kahowa.
- 啥 步行 - 你确定
- What, on foot? - Are you sure?
我们得走一周才能到那儿
It'd be a week before we get there.
除非我们遇见一匹走丢了的脱缰的马
Unless we come across a poach straying prison horses.
那也没有走丢这么远的
ain't no poach that far over.
是啊 队长
Right, Captain.
没了这船可就他妈蛋疼了啊
Losing this boat is god damn stinking.
再者说里族也没那么傻
Besides the Rees ain't that stupid...
如果我们留着它 可以把它堆在我们的底盘周围备用
If we keep it, we can lay it up around hours peak.
别假装知道自己在说啥了 菲兹杰拉德
Quit acting like you know what you're talking about Fitzgerald.
又没人跟你说话
ain't nobody talking to you.
反正也没人听你说
Who'd listen to you anyway.
狗日的 连一颗土豆都他妈没有
God damn, can't even... find fucking... potato shit...
我只想说…
All I'm saying is...
如林营也离这儿不远了
camp Roollin is just up away...
我们可以在那儿稍事休息
And we can hold up there.
我们步行
We walk.
还能怎么着 只能走着呗
Yeah, I'm sure we will.
他娘的 真希望我爹是个医生
God damn, wish my daddy was a doctor,
这样他就能给我买个队长当了
then he could have bought me a captains job.
所以我们现在干啥
So what do we do now?
祈祷这口锅不会乱跑 万一我们会回来
Praying that poacher ain't rocking if we ever get back here...
- 拿上它 - 确保这个地方做好了记号
- to pick them up. - Make sure to mark this place.
我们要在这些石头底下埋点宝贝
We're leaving a fortune under these rocks.
这儿没地儿了 你得往岗子上去
No more room here, you gotta move up the hill.
格拉斯 把路线画下来
Glass. Chart a course...
竭尽全力 尽量让我们避开里族
Try as you can figure to get us around the Ree.
好的 长官
Yes sir.
这不对 这不对
This ain't right, this ain't right.
咱们都清楚回来的时候这些皮子都不会在这儿了
We all know that this furs ain't won't be here by the time we come back.
咱们没法把皮子都带回堡子里
There is no way we can hold them all the way back to the Fort.
阿里卡拉族即里族
且不说接下来的路 阿里卡拉族
Not the way we're going, besides Arikara is...
到处扩张他们的地盘 我们得腾出双手来
spread all through their territory, we want to go with our hands free.
我在努力告诉你们皮子要保不住了
I'm trying to tell you're gonna lose this pelts.
你是要皮子还是要命
Would you rather hold on to the pelts or your life?
命
Life?
你说什么命 我没有命
What life you talking about? I ain't got no life.
只有这些皮子 它们就是我的命
I just got living the only way I get to do that is through this pelts.
操
Fuck!
淡定 菲兹
Calm there, Fitz.
让让路 我要回家了
Make a way, I'm going home...
像骡子一样干了六个月的活
After six months working my ass of like a mule,
冒着掉脑袋的风险
risking my neck...
人死了 图个啥
Men dying and for what?
几乎他妈啥也没留住
Damn nearly lost everything.
这份差事一开始就操蛋
This job's been fucked from the start.
还有一位操蛋的人
There is the one being fucking us.
小伙子们 你们哪位好奇里族为什么发难？
Any of you boys wonder how Ree managed to get their drop on us...
格拉斯先生在这儿呢
for Mr. Glass here,
他是负责留神这种操蛋事情的人
was supposed to be looking out for that fucking thing.
格拉斯曾与波尼族通婚
还有他波尼族的小伙伴
All them Pawnee buddies of his.
波尼族和我们一样讨厌里族
Pawnees as much against Rees as the rest of us.
是嘛
Yeah?
那么他那位混血儿子呢
What about his little half-breed son?
你们觉得他妈妈会不会是野蛮人？
And what kind of savage you think his momma was.
别说了 菲兹
Lay of the boy, Fitz.
我就是想说
All I'm saying here.
野蛮人就是野蛮人
Savage is savage...
嘿 格拉斯
Hey, Glass.
他们说的是真的吗？说你射杀了一名中尉
Is it true what they say? That you shooting a lieutenant...
那会儿你和土著住在一起
While you was living with them savages?
菲兹杰拉德
Fitzgerald.
21名士兵阵亡 至少40个土著死掉
21 dead soldiers, more than 40 dead feather necks...
但只有你和你儿子活着走了出来
But you and your boy are the only ones to get walk out alive.
简直是奇迹 你不觉得吗
It was kind of a miracle, don't you think?
你得闭嘴了 菲兹杰拉德
You need to shut up, Fitzgerald.
这就是你干的
Is that what you did?
射杀你的同类 就为了就这么一条小家伙
Shot one of your own to save this little dog right here?
你想打架吗孩子
You want to fight son?
你玩弄这个小男孩的妈妈
You were playing with this little boy's momma?
- 菲兹杰拉德 - 只好杀了她
- Fitzgerald! - Need to kill her?
嘿 我跟你说话的时候 你可以先不擦来复枪
Hey you can quit polishing that rifle, while I'm talking to you.
我正忙着呢
I'm working on it.
就不能等我跟你说完话你再忙么
You can work on it later when I'm done talking to you.
印第安人有割失败者头皮的习俗 此处讽刺格拉斯为保住头皮而入赘波尼族
- 看着我 头皮 - 够了
- Look at me, scalp. - That's enough!
你忘了你的地位了 小伙
You're forgetting your place boy.
至少在我看来我的地位就摆在这儿
As far as I can tell my place is right here,
在这尖尖的枪头上
on the smart end of this rifle.
归队行进 菲兹杰拉德
You move along, Fitzgerald.
这是命令
That's an order.
听我说
Listen to me.
再过几个小时就天黑了
We only have a couple hours of light left.
我们得把皮子藏起来
We gotta stash these pelts...
还得把船扔掉 走吧
And get rid of the boat, let's go.
好的 队长
Yes, Captain.
我告诉过你要低调点 儿子
起码…
如果你想活命的话 就把嘴闭上
- 他们不会听你说话 - 起码他听得见我…
他们只会看见你这张脸的肤色
明白了吗
明白
你必须听我的 孩子 你必须听话
贝克特
Beckett.
威斯顿
Weston.
他们为什么不跳
Why are they not jumping?
看来他们改主意了
It looks like they changed their minds.
这帮狗娘养的还挺聪明的
Smart sons of bitches.
挺聪明的
Smart...
我本该在船上的
I ought to be on that boat.
你做的没错
You did the right thing.
该走了
起来
咱们该出发了
就来
你最好还是躺会儿吧
其他人好了的时候 让他们到我这儿来
我往西去
你是我儿子
这儿只有两个
波瓦卡不在这儿
可能别人把她带走了
他们去北边了
我们会到山上探探他们的足迹
这法子能行吗
Was it the right decision...
船都不要了
Leaving the boat?
里族占了那条河
Ree own that river.
他们会包抄我们的
Would have flanked us.
如果我们沿着山脉的东侧走
If we stay east to the ground to those mountains...
可以省出一周的时间
We cut a week of our trip.
那儿的土都是干的 里族没有可猎杀的东西
Land is all dry up there, nothing for the Ree to hunt.
- 除了我们 - 除了我们
- Except us? - Except us.
菲兹杰拉德说的是真的吗？
Is it true what Fitzgerald said?
你是因为这个才跑到这穷乡僻壤的吗
Is that why you came out here to the edge of the world?
格拉斯 我不喜欢沉默
Glass? I didn't like the quiet.
你儿子 他经历了不少…
Your boy, he's seen a lot...
他还有个母亲要你带他去找吗？
He got a mother you need to get him back to?
格拉斯 嘿这儿有几只幼崽
Glass!? Hey there are cubs here.
格拉斯
Glass!
这儿有几只幼崽
We got cubs here.
天啊
Christ almighty.
嘿 你
Hey you.
嘿
Hey!
他在这儿呢
He's down here.
- 搭把手… - 看清楚了 这熊还活着
- Help me out... - Keep your eyes open, the bear's alive.
来 我需要你帮忙
Come on, I need your help now.
格拉斯
Glass.
我的天哪
Oh my god!
- 哦天哪 - 队长
- Oh Christ! - Captain.
快把碎布条给我
Give me rags now!
压住出血处
Push where he bleeds out.
准备好工具
Prepare the kit.
布里杰 你把着那儿
Bridger, you hold that.
- 放松 - 哦天哪
- Easy. - Oh God!
他竟然能把这头灰熊放倒
Gotta give him credit for taking that Grizz down with him.
他就不应该开枪
He shouldn't have fire the shot,
这地方全他妈是土著…
the whole place is crawling with fucking tree niggers...
嘿 你够了 你给我适可而止
Hey that's enough, that's enough!
我们还在里族的地盘上呢
We're still on Ree territory here...
他是我们的一员 他妈的
This is one of our own men, goddamm it.
你们离开他 围在四周警戒
The boy leave him, just got a circle around us.
西边和北边 你带他们俩去
North and west, take those two with you.
比尔 弗莱曼 你们去南边和东边
Bill, Fryman, you take South and East.
小心可能有人听到了枪响
Watch for anyone that might have heard that shot.
- 是 长官 - 我们得把伤口缝上
- Yes sir. - We have to stitch him up.
那我呢
What about me?
没事
It's alright.
- 你得… - 你就待在这儿
- You have to... - You stay here.
- 压住 - 抱歉 格拉斯先生 我很抱歉
- Hold it down. - I'm sorry, Mr. Glass. I am so sorry.
布里杰 扶着他 按住这儿
Bridger, hold him. Press down here.
这儿也在流血
He is bleeding down here too.
操他妈的畜生玩意儿
Torturing the bastard.
最该做的… 还是早把他解决了好
The proper thing to do would be though... Finish him off quick.
除非他有痊愈的可能
Unless he has a chance of pulling through.
痊愈 你看那熊给他咬的
Pulling thru? You saw what that Grizz did to him.
他不用一个小时就死透了
He'll be dead inside an hour.
是啊 我们再这么晃悠下去也会死透的
Yeah, we all will be if we don't quit waving like that.
朝着你 然后朝那个方向 我来把着他 来
Towards you and toward that place. I'll hold him. Go.
扶住他 你来
Hold him, you go.
上啊 现在
Go! Now!
- 他昏过去了 - 很好
- He past out. - Very good.
我要趁现在缝合伤口 让我看看
I'm gonna take advantage and stitch up, let me see.
天哪
Oh God!
水
Water.
布里杰 告诉其他人 今晚我们在这儿露营
Bridger, go tell the others we'll camp here tonight.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
我会一直在这儿…
杜桑 他来了
我以为他来不了了
我很高兴你能成功到达
我们需要马匹和来复枪
我们给你们带来了很多皮子
没有马… 我们之前商量好的
你们想要多少皮子就拿多少
我们需要马匹和来复枪
我还需要一个大波婆姨呢
还要能做饭的…
我们不能给你们马匹
他说什么
我不知道 好像是和马有关的事
给我来点喝的… 带一些威士忌
告诉他不要再问马的事情
和你做生意一直很愉快
我要马匹
没有马匹
能和你交易的只有枪和弹药
告诉他 他再提马的事情 那就没有交易了
你在哪里弄到这些东西的 从美国人那儿？
这些都打上烙印了
这种货我只能给你一半的价格
赶他出去
我说了没有马匹
我们要带走这三匹马
我不想再重复我讲的话
我们的交易里没有马
我劝你最好不要再挑事了
我们有约定的 你必须遵守约定
用法语讲 你跟我讲遵守约定
我告诉你了他是说法语的
那些皮子是偷来的
你们偷走了我们的一切
一切
土地
牲畜
两个白种人潜入了我们村庄 带走了我的女儿 波瓦卡
我们留给你们这些兽皮就是因为我们遵守约定
我带走你的马是为了找我的女儿
随你便 你可以再尝试阻止我
生意归生意
为他们准备五匹马
我要大家在黎明出发
I want everybody up at the crack of dawn.
是的 长官 我明白了
Yes sir. Understood Cap.
估计带着格拉斯走会很吃力
Carrying Glass would be hard.
我们需要尽可能赶在前面
We need to get ahead as far as possible.
我们分成两队
We'll divide into two groups.
菲兹杰拉德 琼斯 弗里曼 你们走河的东岸
Fitzgerald, Jones, Fryman. You take the east side of the river.
安德森 你在前面把风
Anderson you scout up front.
- 爪子可不长眼 - 每个人轮流抬着格拉斯
- That claw don't mourn him. - Everybody else takes turn carrying Glass.
是的 队长
Yes, Captain.
这个爪子不是做给我自己的
They're ain't for me.
别让他掉到水里了
Do not let him into the water...
起来
Get up.
- 滚开 - 这是命令
- Fuck off. - That's an order!
他妈的 别让他掉下来
Goddamm it, don't let him down!
别让他掉下来
Don't let him down.
看着
Watch it.
这坡你准备怎么过？
How are we gonna make it up there?
速度放慢
Slow down a bit.
这会害死我们的 队长
It's killing us Captain.
把他抬高点 布里杰
Lift him, Bridger.
稳一点
Keep it steady...
都稳一点
Everybody.
用力…
And here...
我上去拉…
I'm gonna go up and pull...
用力…
Here...
顶住
Hold it.
够倒霉的 我们这样爬不上去的
Enough of this shit. We'll never make it across land this way.
他在发烧 队长
He is burning out Captain.
队长 你这样不论对我们或者他…
Captain you ain't doing us nor him...
像这样苦熬… 都是没有好处的
no favor... going on suffering like this.
队长
Captain!
队长 这里上面也是一样的状况 我们要原路撤回
Captain, it's all the same up here. We have to go back.
然后另找出路
Find another way.
等等
Hold on.
格拉斯… 休…
Glass... Hugh...
我很抱歉 我很抱歉
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
用那块布挡住他的眼睛 布里杰先生
Plant that rag over his eyes, Mr. Bridger.
- 什么 - 我做不到 先生
- What? - Sir, I can't.
用布挡住他的眼睛
Plant that rag over his eyes.
- 什么 等等 - 抱歉 休
- What, wait. - Sorry, Hugh.
等等先生 我不能这样做
Wait. Sir, I can't do that.
我们怎么能把他留在这里 自己走了
How do we get back without him?
- 他是唯一知道路的人啊 - 他不能再走了
- He's the only one who knows the way. - He can't go any further.
- 把布铺在他的眼睛上 - 等等
- Wave that rag over his eyes. - Wait.
我不能这样做 先生
Sir, I can't.
等等 你不能…
Wait, you can't...
用布盖住他的眼睛
Put a rag over his eyes.
铺在他眼睛上面
Lay it over his eyes.
别过来
Step back.
停下来 亨利先生
Stop, Mr. Henry...
亨利 求你了
Henry, please.
队长 队长…
Captain, Captain...
嘿 霍克
Hey, Hawk!
孩子 淡定
Calm down kid.
淡定
Calm down.
亨利 求你了
Henry, please...
落基山皮革厂发出70美元的悬赏
There's a $70 bonus in the Rocky Mountains Fur Company...
给两个人
for two men, who stays...
他们要陪着格拉斯 陪他度过这一切
back with Glass, to see this through.
- 我留下 - 我也是
- I'll stay. - Me too.
不管有没有钱 我都留下
Money or not, I'll stay.
我想走
I need a third.
抱歉 队长 我还有家要照顾…
Sorry Captain, I have family...
我还没疯
I am not crazy.
队长 只有三个人逃不出里族底地盘
Captain, three men can't hold off a party of Ree.
人太少了
Much less boys.
另外 70美元可不值得让一个人豁出命去
Besides, $70 ain't going by nobody lose their ears.
那就给够100美金
100 then.
正是因为这个人 我们才能活到现在
This man is the only reason we're still alive.
队长 开始的时候我们有45个人呢
Oh Captain, we were 45 men when we started,
现在只剩下10个人了 严格说是9个
now we're 10, almost 9.
他是我的父亲 我的份儿可以给你
He's my father, you can have my share.
我的也可以
Mine too.
我们的份儿都给你
Have our share also.
好了
Alright.
好了 如果布里杰先生也是这样想的话
Alright, if Mr. Bridger feels the same way,
那我会遵循他的意思的
then I'll lead behind of them.
- 你 - 没错
- You? - Yeah.
你已经把我的那份兽皮丢了…
You already lost my share of the pelts...
那时候我没有多少的选择余地 只能做最优的决定
So I don't got much choice but to try make it up some other means.
再说了 多周旋一两天的也改变不了现状
Besides, sticking around for another day or two don't make no difference.
有300美元 至少回家也有个交代
$300, is to get to go home with something.
你们要一直照顾着格拉斯 直到…
Glass is to be cared for until...
懂了吗
Understood?
懂 我向你保证
Yeah. You have my word, understand.
你的人要在天黑之前把他带到斜坡那里
You boys get him down of this slope there...
带他到一个安全的地方
somewhere safe before the dark.
你们听到了的
You heard the boys.
- 菲兹杰拉德 - 队长
- Fitzgerald. - Captain.
尽一切可能保护格拉斯的安全
Glass is to be cared for as long as necessary.
然后给他办一个体面的葬礼 这是他应得的
And a proper burial when it's time. He's earned it.
明白
Understand.
您听了到这风声吗 父亲
你还记得你母亲给你讲的有关风的事情吗
风是无法吹倒一棵有强壮树根的树的
只要你仍存一丝呼吸
我非常想念她
我会一直在这里的
在这里陪着你
只要你还有一丝生存的希望 你就勇敢反抗
你要活下去 一定要活下去
当暴风雨来临之际…
你站在这树前…
如果你看看这些树枝 你也许会看到它们从树上坠落
但是 你却不会看到树干倒下
这300美元能给我带来美好的退休生活
$300 goes along way toward retiring...
300美元按当时价格可买德州土地15平方公里
我要去德州 买一片荒地…
Way down to Texas, buy me a decent piece of land...
在风中开始新的生活
And start pissing in the wind.
快点离开这鬼地方
Getting the hell out of this godforsaken places.
里族的人把你搞成这样的？
Did Ree done that to you?
我随口问问而已
I was just asking.
是啊
They done it.
他们把我那头小牛也带走了
They took their sweet cow with it too.
一开始我没觉得怎样 直到听到…
At the start I didn't feel nothing, I just heard the sound of...
刀在我头骨上刮蹭的声音 你懂的…
knife scraping against my skull, you know...
他们大笑着 挥舞着刀 狂哄着…
They were all laughing and whooping and hollering what not...
然后一片血红…
Then the blood came...
冰冷的感觉开始从我的脸蔓延到我的眼睛…
The cold started streaming down my face and my eyes...
在血里呼吸…
The breathing it in...
被血呛着
choking on it.
那个时候我才意识到
That's when I felt it.
我输的一败涂地
I felt all of it.
他们把我打的头痛欲裂
They got my head turned inside out.
天啊
Jesus.
没错 就像他们对德州的印第安人那样…
Yeah, them Indians down Texas way...
他们抢走你的东西 抢走你的地盘
they may rob you, ain't gonna take your topknot.
什么时候的事了？
When was it?
该死的 你能消停会吗 可以吗
God damn, will you just, would you quit that noise now, will ya?
或者… 放下别弄了
Or just... Leave it.
我一直为你冲锋陷阵
I'm following further back from heading against...
打击那些想杀你的人
the boys on account of tending to you.
我们爬上了那些该死的山 但是风却不停的对着我们呼啸
We got to get up that damn mountain but the wind keeps chasing us down.
如果你已经…
If you're ready...
我可以帮你
Take the sacrament.
做这些圣礼
I can do that for you.
你在等什么呢 格拉斯
What you holding to, Glass?
你知道吗
You know?
如果你现在咽气了
Would be better...
对你我 对大家来说
If you would've take that last breath of yours now.
都是一件好事
For all of us.
可你还在顽强的挣扎
You hung tough.
这的确很了不起
That's something.
我求求你了 格拉斯
I'm begging you, Glass.
里族人已经离我们很近了…
Them Ree, they are so close now I can smell them...
近得我都能闻到他们的味道 我知道你也能闻到的
and I know you can smell them to, when you got to think.
你得为你的儿子着想
You gotta think of your boy.
对吧 因为你这样会害死他的
Alright? Cause you're gonna kill him.
会害死我们所有人
You'll kill all of us.
如果你愿意的话 我可以干掉你
I can muzzle you if you like.
这样你就不用再苦熬着了
Take away the suffering, really quick and easy...
除了我 没有人会知道你放弃了求生欲望
No one has to know that you give up. I do that.
你要做的就是眨眨眼睛
All you gotta to do is blink...
告诉我你愿意
If you want me to do that.
为了保护你的儿子而眨眼
Save your boy and blink.
你肯定会眨眼的
You just have to blink.
太好了
Yeah.
哦 太棒了
Oh yes!
你快祈求快点到那个美妙的神殿去吧 找个好神
You best hope that the good Lord get his ass here quick, huh.
也许他会原谅你的罪过 也许不会…
Maybe he'll forgive your sins, you know maybe he won't...
你可以向上天认罪
You just sudden commend it to the Lord.
向耶稣认罪 那个现实和仁慈的神…
Through Jesus Christ, the Lord of all reality and mercy...
滚开 滚开
Get away. Get away.
你还好吗 吉米 吉米… 快帮忙
You ok? Jim. Jim... Help.
- 救命 - 冷静下来 没事的 你不懂的
- Help. - Calm down. Alright, you don't understand.
- 别开枪 你会他妈害死我们的 - 走开
- Don't shout, you'll get us all fucking killed. - Keep away.
我会告诉吉米和队长你干的好事 你会被吊死的
I'll tell Jim and the Captain what you did and they'll hang you.
- 你得明白… - 他们会吊死你…
- You have to understand this... - They'll hang you...
吉米救命 吉米快来这里
Jim help. Jim get over here.
闭嘴
Keep quiet!!
该死
Shit.
找到一个海狸洞
Got one beaver hold.
他的呼吸好点没？
His breathing changed?
我没注意
I ain't noticed.
该死的 他冷的像冰一样
Damn, he's cold as ice.
来 格拉斯先生… 这个能帮你…
Here Mr. Glass... This will help...
能帮你保持温暖
It will keep you warm.
没错
It's alright.
霍克去哪了？
Where is Hawk?
他没和你在一起？
He ain't with you?
- 没有 - 没有？
- No. - No?
我明白的 格拉斯先生
I understand, Mr. Glass.
好了
Alright.
我觉得我们应该点火取暖
I think I'm gonna get a fire going.
嗯 这听上去像个好主意
Yeah, sounds like a good idea.
霍克
Hawk!
你你杀了我儿子
You killed my son.
霍克
Hawk!
布里杰 他们在河流那边大约有20人
Bridger, there's about 20 of them down by the creek.
正在朝我们的方向来
They're headed this way.
现在快点带上你的东西 我们走
Now grab your shit and let's go.
妈的 等一下 这可怎么办？
Shit. Wait. What do we do?
快点跑
Run right now.
- 霍克怎么办？- 我们不用担心他了
- What about Hawk? - He ain't our problem no more.
我们不能把格拉斯丢在这里啊
We can't just leave him here.
他头皮早晚不保
He's going to be scalped.
如果里族人能找到我们 也会找到他
If that Ree can find us, can't he?
等等 那格拉斯怎么办？
Wait. What about Glass?
他也不再是我们的要担心的啦
He ain't our problem no more,
他和我们一样 得靠自己了
he is like us, he's on his own.
不 不 我们向队长保证过的…
No, no, we made a promise to Captain...
要给他办一个体面的葬礼
I'll give him a proper burial when the time is needed.
喂 那是他的猎枪
Well, he needs that rifle.
他现在这个样子 给他大炮都打不响
He can't do nothing with it if you tarred it to his hands.
现在赶快带上你该死的装备 我们走
Now come on get your shit. Let's go.
不 不 我们不能这样
No, no, we can't do this.
- 我们他妈的没有选择了 - 我们不能这样 看看他
- We got no fucking choice. - We can't. Look at him.
- 好吧 你这个该死的… - 你在干什么？
- Alright, shitting brain... - What you doing?
你想带上他 得了吧
Can you take him? Come on.
不 不 等等
No, no wait...
淡定 停下来 菲兹…
Easy, slowly, Fitz...
冷静
Easy.
- 我不能… - 该死…
- I can't... - Damn...
该死的 我让你如愿以偿
Shit, get this shit.
等等 住手 等等
Wait, hold... Hold on!
闭嘴
Shut up.
住手
Hold on.
菲兹…
Fitz...
- 你在干什么 - 你看不到我在干什么吗？
- What are you doing? - What it looks like I'm doing?
给他一个体面的葬礼
A proper burial.
让他如愿以偿啊
Like he wanted.
- 不 不能这样 - 为什么不能？
- No, not like this. - Why not?
他还活着 菲兹 他还没死
He is alive, Fitz. He's alive.
那就用枪打死他
So shoot him.
我真的得走了 我真的得走…
I have to go, I have to...
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我真的很抱歉
队长 来这边…
Captain, this way...
这边有一条可以下来的路
There's a path down here.
那边下不去的
There's no way through down here.
那边是下不去的 我们得爬过去
There ain't shit down there, we go climb over.
谁说可以穿过去的
Cross can go to hell.
- 地图指我们怎么走 - 接着爬
- What does the map say? - Keep climbing.
我们得继续爬 队长
We climb, Captain.
我们得一直爬
We keep climbing.
直到我们到达堡子
Until we reach our gate.
爬吧
Climb.
- 你从墨菲那里来的 - 是的
- You got away from Murph? - Yeah.
你在这等着
You wait for it.
队长
Captain.
长官 墨菲说没有路可以到那里
Sir. Murphy says there's a way down there.
那我们要跟着谁走
Who we following?
你想跟谁就跟谁
You follow who you want.
我就来
I'm going up.
我们要跟上了 布莱尔 过来
We all need to be going up. Blair, come here!
我不会离开你的 儿子
我就在这里
火灭了
Fire's done.
但是我还是感觉不到我的脚…
I can't still feel my feet...
再说了 我们现在和里族人拉的距离还不够远吗
Besides, didn't we put enough distance between us and them Ree anyhow?
是这样的…
Well...
12个里族人还是能以我们两倍的速度前进
a dozen Ree could still made twice the good time as we can.
- 是20 - 什么
- 20. - What?
我记得一之前说是看到了20个里族人
I thought you said that you saw 20 Ree before.
呃 你在说什么
Yeah, what you talking about?
是你把我叫醒的
You woke me up?
然后你跟我说你在河边看到了20个里族人
You said you saw 20 Ree down by the creek.
好吧 20个 12个 有什么关系呢…
Well yeah, 20 or dozen, it don't matter...
我又不是到河边闲逛的
I wasn't gonna exactly hang around the creek counting fucking feathers, now would I?
说真的
Matter a fact.
你一个人去河边干什么？
What was you doing down by the creek all by yourself?
我记得我已经打好了足量的水了
I thought I already brought up plenty of water.
嘿
Hey!
菲兹杰拉德 回答我的问题
Answer me Fitzgerald, I asked you a question.
不要追究了 我们都因为
Don't go questioning me now on the account of fact...
把格拉斯留在那里感到内疚
that we all feel guilty about leaving this Glass behind.
快回答我 不然我一枪打爆脑袋
Answer me or I'm gonna blow your head off.
你忘了 孩子
You got a short memory boy.
如果不是我的话 你的尸体现在还有可能漂在
Your ass is still be floatin around Missouri right now...
密苏里河那里
If it wasn't for me.
现在你又要追究我…
Now wanna ask questions...
你自己都没想明白凭什么质疑我
What you want ask if you won't know asking.
你想知道为什么自己会把格拉斯留在那里等死
You want to know why you left Mr. Glass back there for dead, hah?
也许…
Maybe...
你想知道 就算把小伙伴留在那里了
while you left your little boy friend wandering around,
他也依然有可能活着
you don't know if he's still alive yet. That what you want to know?
就算我骗了你 也是因为你还不是一个男人
I'll tell you lies because you ain't a man yet.
好吗 因为你还会吓得尿裤子
Alright? Because you were scared shitless...
你现在就很害怕 放下你的枪
and you're scared now. Now put your rifle down.
- 那些里族人 - 怎么了
- The Ree. - What off it?
现在对我说真话 你真的看到有里族人？
Tell me right now and be honest. Did you see them?
- 放下你的枪 - 你真的看到有里族人了吗
- Put your rifle down. - Did you see the Ree?
没有
No.
一个都没看到
Not a single one.
你他妈的骗我
You fucking lie to me?
你骗我
You lie to me!
是时候该震慑你一下了 孩子
I had to scare some sense into you boy.
现在格拉斯死了 霍克的情况我们还不清楚…
Now Glass was dead, Hawk we don't know about...
我们都没有必要死在这里… 你明白了吗
There is no point either of us dying here... Do you understand?
依我看来 我救了你两条命 孩子
The way I see it, I saved your life twice now son.
我对你来说就是上帝
I ought to be God to you...
我可以救你 也能让你死在这里
And God giveth, God taketh away.
该死
Shit.
他妈的
Fuck.
下次 如果你要射别人
Next time, if you want to shoot somebody...
你最好用 你最好用火药
you might wanna use, you might wanna use powder.
准备好你的枪
Prime your rifle.
别躺着了
Come on...
快起来 拿好你的东西
let's get up. Grab your shit.
新鲜的血液 可能是波瓦卡的
一个死了的男孩
一个里族男孩
走吧
队长等等
Captain wait...
- 谁干的 - 我不知道啊
- Who did this? - I don't know.
有可能是莱文沃斯队长的军队干的
Could be Captain Leavenworth boys.
哼 有可能
Hmm, yeah.
要注意你的身后
You put some eyes on the back of your head.
这些印第安人永远死不绝
These Indians ain't never as dead as you'll think they are.
看看他们 永远臭烘烘的死样
Look at them, they're always stinking of shit.
这有几匹马
We got horses over here.
好的 布里杰
Alright, Bridger.
我们有马了
We got horses.
这些猪怎么办
What you wanna do about this pigs?
孩子啊 上帝站在我们这边了
Lord is on our side kid.
你还好么小子
You alright there kid?
没瞎琢磨吧
You're head in the right place?
没
I guess.
- 一直在想咱们做得对不 - 不
- Can't help thinking about whether we did the right... - No,
现在不该犹豫
ain't our place to wonder.
上帝给我们指了路 我们没得选
Good Lord's got us on the road, whether we chose or not.
我父亲一直不相信宗教
My Pa being one... wasn't a religious man you, you know?
如果你不种地 不杀生 不暴殄之类的教义…
If you couldn't grow it, or kill it or eat it...
他就是不信
then he just plain all didn't believe in it and that was it.
直到有一次 他去旧萨博山
And this one time he hit on up the old Saber hills.
圣萨博山
San Saber Hills...
和几个德克萨斯的骑手一起去打猎
Joined up with a couple of Texan range buddies of his to hunt, you know.
很平常的一次打猎 他们都打了好几百次了
Pretty routine, you know, they done it like hundred times before.
本应该是3天的杀戮
Should have been three days of kill,
但是周六那天 全毁了
but on Saturday, well it all went fucked.
不知怎么 那天他不得不失去些弟兄
Somehow that night he has to lose buddies...
首先
And on top of it all...
科曼奇族的人抢了他们的马 所以
The Comanche's they went and took the horses, so...
他快饿死了
He was starving,
接近崩溃
delirious...
一直爬 爬到一堆泥土里
And crawls up into this mud...
除了有几棵树就什么都没有的地方
Like the group of trees out there in the middle of nowhere...
就在那一片垃圾中支着
just sticking up in this ocean of scrub...
突然他就信了
And he found religion.
那一刻
At that moment...
他告诉我
he told me...
他看到了上帝
He found God.
结果呢
It turns out...
他所说的上帝
The God...
是个松鼠
He is a squirrel.
哈 笑死我了
Yeah. Then go meet him one...
后来他就经常说遇到了上帝
I found God, he used to say.
他坐着那儿
Who has sitting and basking...
像是得到了救赎一样
in glory in subliminal mercy...
我一枪把他那个狗娘养的干掉了
I shot knee that son of a bitch...
孩子 咱们该休息了
Yeah, you might wanna close your eyes kid.
我受伤了
你干嘛了
熊
一只灰熊
A Grizzly.
我的同伴把我丢下等死
杀了我的儿子
我也失去了我的家人
苏族屠杀了我的族人
我打算去南部找到更多波尼族的人
我的心在滴血…
但是君子报仇十年不晚
你跟我一起走…
你的身体都快溃烂了
需要治疗一下
要不你会死的
太好了
Yeah!
终于回来了
There she is.
我们活着回来咯
We did it.
你应感到自豪
You ought to be proud of yourself boy.
嗯
Yeah.
我们遵从了命令 只是暂时没办葬礼
Well we followed orders... We just kept the funeral apart.
别一下去就变得跟没良心的一样
Don't go down there starting going no kind no conscience, alright?
稍不注意我们就会人头落地
Cause sure is neither come will have us both swinging from couple grants.
我们仁至义尽了
Now, we did what we had to do.
因为时间充裕 我们又深挖了几尺
We had the extra day, so we managed to dig a little deeper...
搬了一些石头在上面以防拾荒的发现他的尸体
leave some rocks on top, so that the scavengers couldn't get out to him...
我们该做的都做了
we was done right and all.
他被埋葬的好好的
He was buried right.
- 先生 - 其实是这样
- Sir... - The truth is that, ah...
当霍克消失的时候 我就担心拾荒的人来着
When Hawk disappeared, I was worried about the savages.
我都准备好撤退了 你知道么 但
I was ready to get... moving on out you know, but...
布里杰说要留下
Bridger here, he argued to stay.
他说要等等
He argued to stay so that...
可以做一个十字架什么的
He could at least build the cross, or something...
可以放在格拉斯的墓上 然后他就做了一个
To put on top of Glass's grave, and that's what he did...
- 就是这么回事儿 - 很高兴你活着回来 布里杰
- That's what we did. - Glad to hear you pulled your weight, Mr. Bridger.
我就知道你回得来
I know you would.
他不光活着回来了 而且
Yeah, well, more than he pulled his weight, Captain, is...
一路上帮了我很多
this man here, he was my partner.
好的吧
Alright.
当时说好的条约都履行了？
Am I to assume that there was agreed arrangement did not changed?
都履行了
Fortunately for me it did not, no.
谢谢
Thank you.
为了奖励你的勇敢 荣誉
For your courage, honor...
- 和你的服务 - 耶
- And service. - Yeah.
不管怎么说 布里杰 你行为值得奖励
Deal or no deal? Mr. Bridger, you deserve something for what you did.
十分感谢
Thank you.
这孩子一路上没少吃苦
Kid's been beating himself up of the bag hole trip.
我们都看出来格拉斯身体那样了
We all saw the shape Glass was in,
没什么可为他做的了 对吧？
it was no more to be done, right?
没错
Yeah.
都看出来了
We all saw it.
当风暴来袭的时候…
你站在树前…
你看看他们的枝 你之道它们会掉落
但是你看看他的主干 你就知道他的稳健
我们都是野蛮人
WE ARE ALL WILD
这曾经有生火的迹象…
有生火的迹象…
哪里
在月之森林的入口
可能两天之前来过 他们往东面走了
通知其他人
快点行动 波瓦卡可能和他们在一起
把那姑娘带过来…
那五匹马可不是白送的
别出声
Don't make a sound.
安静点
Be quiet.
我去偷匹马
我要把你蛋割下来
图森特去哪了
给我过来…
- 我能坐这儿么 - 可以
- May I join you? - Yes.
- 真的么 - 真的
- Yeah? - Yes.
我还在想什么时候才能拿到钱
Damn I was wondering when we might be getting paid for that haul?
因为我们的钱还在外面没收回来呢
Cause them pelts we collect, they are still out there...
全都被泥土和雪覆盖着
They're covered with dirt and some snow,
不能怪我
but they are there, and that ain't my fault.
我还在等莱文沃斯队长和他的军队过来呢
I'm waiting for Captain Leavenworth to arrive with his army...
然后我们就有足够的人手
And then we'll have enough men...
再回去教训那帮土著人
To get back out there and shoot some civilization...
拿回属于我们的钱
into those fucking Arikara, get back our pelts.
好好好
Alright, alright.
所以要回去打仗？
And now when is that supposed to happen?
还不清楚 但
I don't know but...
不到那时候 大家都拿不到钱
Until then nobody gets paid.
听我讲
Listen here, alright?
我是被雇来当保镖 不是来打仗的
I was hired to trap them... I wasn't hired to guard them.
我觉得你坐享其成
The way I see it... you got a safe.
- 还有钱拿 - 你签了合同
- Probably full of money. - You signed a contract.
你的责任就是保护你的老板和你老板的东西
To protect your boss and your boss's property.
现在我的东西不安全 还多花了300美元
And that safe isn't full anymore, it's short about $300.
多花了？什么意思我不懂
Short? Short? What the hell is that supposed to mean?
根据我的记录 你为了这次出行
It means according to my cash records, You purchased more goods on the expedition...
提前采购的东西比你的薪水还多
than what you are owed by the company.
新年快乐啊 菲兹杰拉德
Happy New Year, Fitzgerald.
菲兹杰拉德杀了我的儿子
FITZGERALD KILLED MY SON
外面有个白人
White man at the gate.
你好 你谁啊
What's up? Who you are?
我没武器 我没有武器
I have no weapon, I have no weapons.
- 道布 把队长找来 - 我没有武器
- Dobb, get the Captain. - I have no weapon.
你身边的其他人呢
Where are your men?
- 死了 全都死了 - 谁干的？
- Dead, all dead. - Who was he?
我不知道 能给我点吃的么？
I don't know, something to eat please.
食物收费
Food comes at price.
- 可我没钱啊 - 那就没得吃 懂了么
- I have no money. - Then you don't eat this, see how that works.
或者你可以给我们你印第安人那儿偷过来的钱
Maybe you can give back some of them stolen pelts you buy from the Indians.
- 别闹了 琼斯 - 银子
- Not now, Jones. - Silver.
我这有银子
This is silver.
我来看看
Oh yeah?
这是所有
This all you got?
我们原来有9个人 我朋友死在雪里了
We was 9... But my friend he died in the snow...
然后其他的
And the others were...
被狼… 全都被狼…
By wolves... by wolves...
等等 这是哪弄到的？
Wait where did you get this?
这水壶
The canteen.
他 落在了地上
He... he drop it in the snow.
- 谁 谁 - 我不知道 我没看到 没看到
- Who, who? - I do not know, I don't see. I don't see.
有可能是霍克
It could be Hawk.
真有可能
Yeah, it could be.
- 也有可能是威斯顿 - 离这里多远？
- Maybe it was the Weston. - How far from here?
- 离这里多远？- 13英里
- How far from here? - 13 miles...
西北方向… 离黄石很近
Northwest... Near the Yellowstone.
备马
Get the horses saddled.
火把和补给 10美元一个人的量
Torches and supplies, $10 a men.
- 安德森 你待在这 - 遵命
- Anderson, you stay here. - Yes, sir.
看着他 喂饱它
-Feed him and watch him...
我给你拿杯水
I'll get you a drink.
开大门
Open the gate.
随时准备应战
Keep your guard up.
眼睛看着前面
Eyes in front.
别急别慌
Nice and easy.
慢慢的
Slow.
来者何人
Who are you?
贝克特 是你么？
Beckett? Is that you?
威斯顿
Weston?
格拉斯
Glass.
- 是格拉斯 - 格拉斯
- That's Glass... - Glass...
好了好了
It's okay.
天啊
Jesus Christ.
天啊 发生了什么
Jesus Christ, what happened?
他在哪？
Where is he?
约翰 带上他 回家
Johns take him, go.
快走 我带路
Go, I'm riding ahead.
- 菲尔 - 带上布里杰
- Phil. - Take Bridger.
带上布里杰
Take Bridger.
- 你会没事儿的 格拉斯 - 快走
- You got it, Glass. - Go.
开大门
Open the gate.
- 你看到菲兹杰拉德了么 - 没有
- Have you seen Fitzgerald? - No, sir.
快起来
Get up.
起来
- 你们看到菲兹杰拉德了么 - 没 没看到
- Have you seen Fitzgerald? - No sir.
菲兹杰拉德
Fitzgerald.
- 这是要干嘛 - 他去哪了？
- Oh, easy. - Where did he go?
- 谁 - 菲兹杰拉德
- Who? - Fitzgerald.
他去哪了？
Where did he go?
- 我不知道 - 不告诉我我现在就杀了你
- I have no idea. - Tell me or I'll take your head off.
- 队长 我向天发誓 - 快说
- Captain, I swear to God. - Tell me!
- 快告诉我 - 德克萨斯
- Tell me! - Texas.
- 德克萨斯 - 他说他会去德克萨斯
- Texas? - He said he was going to Texas.
我发誓 他说他要重新入伍
I swear to God, he said he was going to re-enlist.
然后他提到了一块很不错的土地
And he start talking of a property, a decent piece of land...
他真的去德克萨斯了 我发誓
He's heading to Texas. I swear to god.
待着别动
Stay here.
菲兹杰拉德
Fitzgerald.
他妈的
Goddamm it.
开门
Open the gate.
把门打开
Open her up.
快去叫队长
Get Captain.
快带他去医生那 快
Get him to the doctor, now.
你告诉我他死了
You said he was dead.
- 你说他死了 - 我以为他死了 真的
- You said he was dead. - I thought he was dead, I swear.
- 你他妈个骗子 - 他对我撒谎
- You're a liar. - He lied to me.
骗子 你弃他而不顾
Liar, you left. You left him out there.
- 我以为他… - 祈祷吧
- I thought he was... - Say the Lord's prayer.
- 什么 - 快祈祷吧
- What? - Say the Lord's prayer.
我们的先祖
Our father...
没有到达天堂… 我不…
Who arent in heaven... I can't...
闭嘴
Shut up.
闭嘴 从现在起 你就是背叛大家的犯人
Shut up! From here on you are a prisoner charged with treason.
把他关起来 把他关起来
Take him to the cage. Take him to the cage!
你要么快动 要不我就开枪了
You handle or I'll shoot him!
我以为他要死了
I thought he was gonna die.
- 快起来 - 医生
- Get up. - Doc.
我能帮忙 求求你了
I could help, please.
- 队长… 求求你了 - 天啊
- Please, Captain... - God!
好了 快点
Alright. Come on.
一二三
1, 2, 3
划 划 划
Slide, slide. Slide.
- 他身体怎么样了- 他会好起来的 伤口肿了而已
- How is he? - He'll be fine, but there is swelling...
需要静养
needs to rest.
我待会去看看他
I'll be back to check up on him.
他跑路了 是不是？
He ran off, didn't he?
布里杰说的是实话
Bridger is telling the truth...
- 此话怎讲 - 菲兹杰拉德撒谎了
- How is that? - Fitzgerald lied to him...
他只是被胁迫了
He was just following orders.
当菲兹杰拉德捅死我儿子的时候 他不在现场
He wasn't there when Fitzgerald stabbed my boy to death.
真的么？他杀了霍克？
Is that what happened? He killed Hawk?
我需要一匹马 一杆枪
I need a horse and a gun.
不 你需要休息 然后好好吃饭
No, you need to rest and something to eat.
- 我负责追上他 - 不行
- I'm going after him.- No.
没有我 你找不到他
You'll never find him without me.
如果我们多等一天的话 他就又多一天的时间逃走
If we wait till morning he'll have a day head start and he get away.
不 他不会的
No he won't.
他害怕了
He's afraid.
他知道他逃不过我这截了
He knows how far I came for him.
就像麋鹿一样 一害怕就躲进丛林
Same as that elk, when they get afraid they run deep in to the woods...
我抓住它的尾巴了 他还
I got him trapped, he just...
- 他还不知道- 你怎么能确定
- He doesn't know it yet. - How can you be so sure?
因为他还有所恋
Cause he got everything to lose.
我的儿子是我的唯一
All I had was that boy...
他从我手中夺走了他
And he took him from me.
我不能让你这样去找他
I can't let you go back out there.
- 这次不会了 - 不
- Not again. - No.
我再也不畏惧死亡了
I ain't afraid to die anymore.
我已经死过了
I've done that already.
让我跟你一起吧
I'm going with you.
这是他马的足迹 没错
It's his horse, alright. Yeah.
他不可能夜晚行动
No way he could have ridden through the night.
还有多远
How far ahead?
- 最多半天 - 这足迹也有可能是里族人的
- Half a day at the most. - Could be Ree.
如果这不是他的足迹 我们就跟丢了
If they aren't his, we lose him.
他必须得重新入伍 然后才能继续合法的杀人
He must get re-enlisted so he can justify killing again.
这些印记是他的
This tracks right here are his.
走吧
Come on.
我都不记得我妻子的面容了
I can't remember my wife's face.
上周她还和我在一起
Last week she was still with me.
但是现在不在了
Now she's gone.
我怕我回去之后都认不出来她了
I worry I won't recognize her when I get back home.
你真的杀了一个警官么？
Is it true you killed an officer?
我只是杀了一个想杀掉我儿子的人
I just killed a man who was trying to kill my son.
- 烟 - 多远？
- Smoke.- How close?
1英里内
No more than a mile up that way.
我从西边过 你从东面包夹
I'm gonna head up to the west you go down to the east...
- 看看能不能找到什么线索 - 如果是里族人的呢
- See if we can find some tracks. - What if it's the Ree?
如果是里族人 我们掉头回来在这集合
If it's the Ree, you turn right back around and meet me back here.
没想到百里迢迢的
I wouldn't expect to find a man of your stature...
您会大驾光临
so far away from his stove when...
队长 这么冷的清晨你迷路了么
the morning is so cold as this. Captain, are you lost?
我是来带你回堡子的
I'm here to take you back to Fort Kahowa.
然后你会受到杀人罪处理
Where you will be trialed for murder.
您说什么
Yes sir?
我不太喜欢您的计划
I ain't crazy about your plan.
而且我还有自己的计划
Besides, I got one of my own.
我们说好的 格拉斯
We had a deal Glass.
我想要说服你儿子来着
I tried to tell your boy, alright?
我想要告诉他发生了什么 可是他不听
I tried to tell him what was happening, but he won't listen...
他一直叫喊 会害死所有人的
And he kept on screaming. And he was gonna get everybody killed.
你和我
You and me...
我们商量好的
we had a deal.
我们都知道那里发生了什么
We all know what happened out there.
我向天发誓
And on my soul to Lord.
上帝知道那里发生了什么
Lord he knows what happened out there.
我们没商量
There was no deal.
你杀了我儿子
You killed my boy.
也许你应该换个男人养养
Maybe you should have raised a man...
而不是是什么娘娘腔
Instead of a some girlie little bitch.
该死的
Goddamm it!
你追我这么远 就为了复仇？
You came all this way just for your revenge?
你好好享受吧 格拉斯
Well you enjoy it, Glass.
反正你的儿子已经死了 回不来了
Cause there ain't nothing gonna bring your boy back.
复仇之剑在上帝的手里…
而不在我的手里